Facilities Management Records UA021
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Facilities Management Records
1849 -- 2004
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
University Facilities
Miller, Russell E.
UA021
12.2 Linear Feet 24 boxes and 14 oversize folders
72 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized in three series: Buildings and grounds; Architectural drawings and plans; and Unprocessed accessions.
Custodial History
The first series contains materials originating in the Facilities Department as well as information collected by Russell Miller while preparing his history of Tufts College, Light on the Hill.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs, drawings, plans, correspondence, maps, newspaper clippings, and publications about Tufts buildings. The bulk of the material deals with the Medford campus.
Biographical / Historical
The Department of Grounds and Buildings was created during the latter half of the nineteenth century, with the purpose of maintaining the grounds and buildings of Tufts College in Medford. As the college grew to include the Schools of Medicine, Dental Medicine, and Veterinary Medicine, responsibility for maintaining the Boston and Grafton Campuses, in addition to the Medford/Somerville Campus, fell to the Department of Grounds and Buildings. The department was renamed the Department of Buildings and Grounds in January 1980. In 1999, the department again underwent a name change, becoming the Tufts University Facilities Department. While still charged with building and ground maintenance, the Facilities Department is also responsible for energy management, recycling, administration of the space inventory system, and planning and implementing maintenance projects.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Facilities
- Buildings and Grounds, 1849 -- 1994; UA021.001; 8.95 Linear Feet; 68 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials collected by Russell Miller while preparing his history of Tufts College, Light on the Hill. It contains correspondence, clippings, and photographs primarily of the Medford campus, including maps and plans. The text of a detailed tour of Goddard Chapel is included.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Buildings, general, 1910 -- 1981; UA021.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    - Study of the campus at Tufts College showing the positions of the present buildings and suggesting possible locations for future buildings, 1932; UA021.001.001.00001.00001; Andrews, Jones, Biscoe, and Whitmore (Box 1)
      this architectural plan accompanies, "A report on the future development of the buildings and grounds at Tufts College"
      Buildings; Plan views; Tufts University
  - Buildings, general, 1936 -- 1982; UA021.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Art objects, art collection and exhibits, 1981 -- 1983; UA021.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Art objects, furniture, 1946 -- 1983; UA021.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Art objects, Brooklyn Museum, 1936 -- 1968; UA021.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Pencil sketch for the 1899 gate, 1901 -- 1909; UA021.001.001.00006 (Box Shared 36)
    This item was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversize materials. Text on poster: "H.G. Ripley, architect. 8 Beacon St."
  - College Buildings: Plaques and Tablets, 1938 -- 1959; UA021.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings, early records, 1849 -- 1899; UA021.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings: Alumnae Hall, 1929 -- 1967; UA021.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings, Alumni House, 1963; UA021.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings, Anderson Hall, 1958 -- 1972; UA021.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings: Arena Theater (old Jackson Gym), 1924 -- 1951; UA021.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings, Asian House, 1977; UA021.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings, Bacon Hall, 1964 -- 1978; UA021.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings, Ballou Hall (1), 1897 -- 1973; UA021.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - College Buildings, Ballou Hall (2), 1856 -- 1982; UA021.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and grounds, photos, 1880 -- 1975; UA021.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
    - Aerial view of Wessell Library, Goddard Chapel, and Eaton Hall, 1967; UA021.001.002.00011.00001; Lowry, Laurence (Box 2)
      Aerial views; Tufts University
  - Ballou photos, 1939 -- 1983; UA021.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Ballou photos, 1900 -- 1960; UA021.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
    - Frontal View of Ballou Hall, 1908; UA021.001.003.00002.00001; Unknown (Box 3)
      Academic; Administrative; Buildings; Dormitories; Exterior views; Trees; Tufts University
  - Ballou photos, 1856 -- 1900; UA021.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
    This date is approximate.
  - Ballou photos, 1900 -- 1985; UA021.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - College Buildings, Barnum Hall, 1884 -- 1986; UA021.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
    - All that remained of Jumbo after the Barnum Fire on 14 April, 1975; UA021.001.003.00005.00001; Baer, J.C. (Box 3)
      Firefighters; Building sites; Fires; Tufts University
    - Frontal view of Barnum Museum, 1894; UA021.001.003.00005.00002; Unknown (Box 3)
      Buildings; Exterior views; Libraries; Laboratories; Museums; Tufts University
    - Interior view of Barnum Museum with Jumbo, 1889; UA021.001.003.00005.00003; Stebbins, N.L. (Box 3)
      Animals; Elephants; Museums; Rooms; Jumbo; Tufts University
    - Biology laboratory in Barnum Museum, 1894; UA021.001.003.00005.00004; Stebbins, N.L. (Box 3)
      Laboratories; Museums; Rooms; Tufts University
  - College Buildings, Baronian Field House, 1985; UA021.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - College Buildings, Blakeslee House, 1939; UA021.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - College Bookstore, 1920 -- 1988; UA021.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - College Buildings, Braker Hall, 1926 -- 1940; UA021.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
    - Braker Hall, 1926 -- 1940; UA021.001.003.00009.00001; Munro, Melville S. (Box 3)
      Buildings; Tufts University
  - College Buildings, Bray Laboratory, 1946 -- 1951; UA021.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - College Buildings, Bromfield Pearson, photos, 1900 -- 1956; UA021.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
    - Exterior view of Bromfield-Pearson, 1900; UA021.001.003.00011.00001; Unknown (Box 3)
      Academic; Buildings; Exterior views; Trees; Tufts University
    - Machine shop in Bromfield Pearson, 1900; UA021.001.003.00011.00002; Stebbins, N.L. (Box 3)
      Machinery; Rooms; Windows; Tufts University
  - College Buildings, Brown-Durkee House, 1950 -- 1963; UA021.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - College Buildings, Bush Hall, 1959 -- 1964; UA021.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
    - Wall display at Bush Hall, 1964; UA021.001.003.00013.00001; Unknown (Box 3)
    - Bush Hall, 1959; UA021.001.003.00013.00002; Duette (Box 3)
      this date is approximate; identification of building as Bush Hall is uncertain
    - Edith Bush unveiling dedicatory plaque at Bush Hall, 1959; UA021.001.003.00013.00003; Duette (Box 3)
      Buildings; Plaques; Bush, Edith L.; Tufts University
  - Ballou Hall rededication, pencil drawing, 1956; UA021.001.003.00014 (Box Shared 36)
    This item was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008.
    poster
  - Photograph of Bookstore, 1969-09-27; UA021.001.003.00015 (Box Small Map Case 1 Drawer 4)
    This photograph was donated to Tufts on October 22, 2009 by Jeffrey J. King. He is also the photographer. Please see small items donation documentation for correspondence.
    photographic print
  - College Buildings, Campus Center (Elizabeth van Huysen Mayer Campus Center), 1979 -- 1985; UA021.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - College Buildings, Capen House, 1876 -- 1951; UA021.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - College Buildings, Carmichael Hall, 1953 -- 1965; UA021.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - College Buildings, Central Heating Plant, photos, UA021.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - College Buildings, Cohen Arts Center, 1955 -- 1980; UA021.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - College Buildings, Cohen Arts Center, Gallery 11, 1986 -- 1987; UA021.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - College Buildings, Chandler House, UA021.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - College Buildings, Chemistry Lab (old) research building, 1908 -- 1936; UA021.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
    - General chemical laboratory in the Chemical Laboratory Building, 1908; UA021.001.005.00006.00001; Unknown (Box 5)
      Bottles; Laboratories; Rooms; photographic print; Tufts University
  - College Buildings, Curtis Hall, 1893 -- 1977; UA021.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
    - Curtis Hall and Post Office, 1900; UA021.001.005.00007.00001; Unknown (Box 5)
      Buildings; Exterior views; Post offices; photographic print; Tufts University
  - College Buildings, Cousens Gym, photos, 1930 -- 1952; UA021.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - College Buildings, Cousens Gym, 1925 -- 1977; UA021.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - College Buildings, Dean Hall, 1886 -- 1963; UA021.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - [No. 10 Dean Hall - Interior Dorm Room Photographs], 1904; UA021.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - Eaton Library, photos, 1908 -- 1981; UA021.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
    - Exterior view of Eaton Memorial Library, 1950; UA021.001.006.00001.00001; Unknown (Box 6)
      This date is approximate
      Buildings; Exterior views; Libraries; Trees; Tufts University
    - Exterior view of Eaton Memorial Library, 1950; UA021.001.006.00001.00002; Unknown (Box 6)
      this date is approximate
      Buildings; Exterior views; Libraries; Tufts University
    - Memorial Library under construction, September, 1949; UA021.001.006.00001.00003; Unknown (Box 6)
      Back of image reads: Memorial Library, Tufts College, Medford Mass., Month of September 1949
      Buildings; Exterior views; Libraries; Construction; Tufts University
    - Construction work on Memorial Library, October, 1949; UA021.001.006.00001.00004; Unknown (Box 6)
      Back of image reads: Memorial Library, Tufts College, Medford Mass., Month of October 1949
    - Memorial Wing, Eaton Library, 1949; UA021.001.006.00001.00005; Unknown (Box 6)
    - Entrance to Eaton Hall, 1950; UA021.001.006.00001.00006; Unknown (Box 6)
    - Eaton Library, 1924; UA021.001.006.00001.00007; Unknown (Box 6)
    - Memorial Library under construction, October, 1949; UA021.001.006.00001.00008; Unknown (Box 6)
    - First floor plan, War Memorial Library, 1949; UA021.001.006.00001.00009; Dirlam, Arland A. (Box 6)
      Buildings; Exterior views; Libraries; Plan views; Tufts University
    - Dedication of War Memorial Library, 1951; UA021.001.006.00001.00010 (Box 6)
      (L to R) Admiral Pride, Mrs. Patton, and Leonard Carmichael.
      Dedication services; photographic print; Carmichael, Leonard
  - Eaton Library, 1904 -- 1981; UA021.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Faculty homes, 1871 -- 1966; UA021.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
    - Delta Tau Delta House or Graves House, 18 Latin Way, 1905; UA021.001.006.00003.00001; Unknown (Box 6)
      Buildings; Exterior views; Greek letter societies; House; Housing; Delta Tau Delta; Tufts University
  - East Hall, 1900 -- 1960; UA021.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Fletcher Hall, 1926 -- 1962; UA021.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Goddard (Gym) Hall, 1884 -- 1938; UA021.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
    Includes postcard of Goddard Gym, sent to Madeline Ellis in July 1908. It was donated to the DCA by Nancy Iovanni in January 2010 (2010.059).
  - A Walking Tour of Goddard Chapel by Rev. Geoffrey G. Drutchas, 1984; UA021.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Goddard Chapel, photos, 1906 -- 1931; UA021.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
    - Illustration of Goddard Chapel, 1906; UA021.001.007.00002.00001; Unknown (Box 7)
      Buildings; Chapels; Tufts University
  - Goddard Chapel, photos, 1900 -- 1965; UA021.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
    - Interior view of Goddard Chapel, 1912; UA021.001.007.00003.00001; Unknown (Box 7)
      Arches; Chapels; Interior views; Rooms; Tufts University
  - Goddard Chapel, photos, 1900 -- 1970; UA021.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Goddard Chapel, photos, 1900 -- 1970; UA021.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Goddard Chapel, general, 1883 -- 1993; UA021.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Goddard Chapel, correspondence, 1880 -- 1981; UA021.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Goddard Chapel, bells, 1898 -- 1984; UA021.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Graves House, 1925; UA021.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Hallowell Hall, 1988; UA021.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Haskell Hall, 1965; UA021.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
    - Haskell Hall, 1965; UA021.001.008.00006.00001; Zimberg, George (Box 8)
      Dormitories; Buildings; Tufts University
  - Henry Clay Jackson Gym, 1945; UA021.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Hill Hall, 1958 -- 1968; UA021.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Hodgdon Hall, 1954; UA021.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
    Includes Jeannette R. Hodgon's book 'Collecting Old English Lustre,' letter of donor Mrs Mark Janett [?spelling] to president Nils Wessel and an undated not by Frances Leighton do Miss Wynne Roberts regarding an exhibit of lustre - these items were found in a drawer in the Art Gallery in December 2010 and transferred to DCA in January 2011.
  - Hooper Infirmary, 1932 -- 1982; UA021.001.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - Houston Hall, 1962; UA021.001.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - Howe Memorial Laboratory, 1900 -- 1957; UA021.001.009.00004 (Box 9)
    - Engine room in power house, 1900; UA021.001.009.00004.00001; Stebbins, N.L. (Box 9)
      Interior views; Machinery; Rooms; Tufts University
  - Kursall, 1940; UA021.001.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Latin Way Dormitory, 1979; UA021.001.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Lewis Hall, 1969 -- 1972; UA021.001.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - MacPhie Dining Hall, 1962; UA021.001.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - Marston Balch Arena Theater, 1991; UA021.001.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - Metcalf Hall, 1893 -- 1966; UA021.001.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - Miller Hall, 1959; UA021.001.009.00011 (Box 9)
  - Milne House, UA021.001.009.00012 (Box 9)
  - Miner Hall, 1891 -- 1956; UA021.001.009.00013 (Box 9)
    - Miner Hall, 1950; UA021.001.009.00013.00001; Duette Photographers (Box 9)
      Buildings; Stairs; Exterior views; Tufts University
  - Mugar Hall, 1950 -- 1970; UA021.001.009.00014 (Box 9)
  - North Hall, 1947 -- 1972; UA021.001.009.00015 (Box 9)
  - Packard Hall, 1874 -- 1979; UA021.001.009.00016 (Box 9)
    - Packard Hall from the north, 1880; UA021.001.009.00016.00001; Unknown (Box 9)
      Buildings; Views; Tufts University
    - Packard Hall with West Hall in the background, 1920; UA021.001.009.00016.00002; Unknown (Box 9)
    - View of Packard Hall and East Hall, 1875; UA021.001.009.00016.00003; Unknown (Box 9)
    - Packard and East Halls, 1890; UA021.001.009.00016.00004; Unknown (Box 9)
    - Postcard of Packard Hall, 1915; UA021.001.009.00016.00005; C.T. (Curt Teich) American Art (Box 9)
      Buildings; Postcards; Tufts University
    - Packard Hall when it was the library, 1885; UA021.001.009.00016.00006; Unknown (Box 9)
      Buildings; Libraries; Exterior views; Tufts University
    - Packard Hall entrance, 1969; UA021.001.009.00016.00007; McLaren, Lynn (Box 9)
      Buildings; People; Exterior views; Tufts University
    - Rear of Packard Hall, 1955; UA021.001.009.00016.00008; Unknown (Box 9)
      Buildings; Exterior views; Tufts University
  - Paige Hall, 1891 -- 1950; UA021.001.009.00017 (Box 9)
  - Pearson Chemical Laboratory, photos, 1922 -- 1960; UA021.001.009.00018 (Box 9)
  - Pearson Chemical Laboratory, 1913 -- 1976; UA021.001.009.00019 (Box 9)
  - Posner Hall, 1954; UA021.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
    - Architectural drawing of Posner Hall, 1954; UA021.001.010.00001.00001; McKim, Mead and White (Box 10)
      Drawings; Dormitories; Tufts University
  - Post Office, 1895 -- 1924; UA021.001.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - President's House, 1938 -- 1976; UA021.001.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Railroad Station, 1880 -- 1959; UA021.001.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - Richardson House, 1920 -- 1936; UA021.001.010.00005 (Box 10)
  - Robinson Hall, 1894 -- 1951; UA021.001.010.00006 (Box 10)
    - Exterior view of Robinson Hall, 1902; UA021.001.010.00006.00001; Unknown (Box 10)
    - Mechanical laboratory in Robinson Hall, 1902; UA021.001.010.00006.00002; Stebbins, N.L. (Box 10)
      Interior views; Laboratories; Machinery; Tufts University
    - Electrical laboratory in Robinson Hall, 1902; UA021.001.010.00006.00003; Stebbins, N.L. (Box 10)
      Electricity; Interior views; Laboratories; Tufts University
    - Drawing room in Robinson Hall, 1902; UA021.001.010.00006.00004; Stebbins, N.L. (Box 10)
      Drawings; Interior views; Rooms; Tufts University
  - Schmalz House, UA021.001.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Shirley and Alex Aidekman Arts Center, includes Tisch Family Gallery, 1991 -- 1993; UA021.001.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - Start House, 1900 -- 1905; UA021.001.010.00009 (Box 10)
  - Stratton Hall, 1926 -- 1959; UA021.001.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Sweet Hall, 1926 -- 1959; UA021.001.010.00011 (Box 10)
    - Sweet Hall, 1955; UA021.001.010.00011.00001; Duette Photographers (Box 10)
      Dormitories; Buildings; Exterior views; Tufts University
  - Tilton Hall, 1960 -- 1962; UA021.001.010.00012 (Box 10)
  - Tufts Administration Bldg. (TAB), 1988; UA021.001.010.00013 (Box 10)
  - Wade House, 1938; UA021.001.010.00014 (Box 10)
  - Wessell Library, photos, 1963 -- 1985; UA021.001.010.00015 (Box 10)
    - Wessell Library roof, 1980; UA021.001.010.00015.00001; Southwick, Peter (Box 10)
      this date is approximate.
      Libraries; Buildings; Tufts University
    - Architects' rendering of Wessell Library, view from Professors Row, 1963; UA021.001.010.00015.00002; Campbell and Aldrich (Box 10)
      Libraries; Buildings; Drawings; Tufts University
    - Architectural model of Wessell Library, buildings and grounds, 1963; UA021.001.010.00015.00003; Campbell and Aldrich (Box 10)
      Libraries; Buildings; Architectural models; Tufts University
  - Wessell Library, photos, 1963 -- 1980; UA021.001.010.00016 (Box 10)
    - Wessell Library, 1966; UA021.001.010.00016.00001; Phokion Karas (Box 10)
      Libraries; Exterior views; Trees; Tufts University
    - Wessell front entrance featuring 'Man and Pegasus' sculpture, 1965; UA021.001.010.00016.00002; Unknown (Box 10)
      Libraries; Statues; Interior views; Tufts University
    - Architects' rendering of Wessell Library, view from Goddard Chapel, 1963; UA021.001.010.00016.00003; Unknown (Box 10)
      Libraries; Drawings; Tufts University
    - Tufts University library competition, upper floor plan, 1963; UA021.001.010.00016.00004; Unknown (Box 10)
      Libraries; Plan views; Tufts University
    - Tufts University library competition, site plan, 1963; UA021.001.010.00016.00005; Unknown (Box 10)
    - Architectural model of Wessell Library, 1963; UA021.001.010.00016.00006; Unknown (Box 10)
      Libraries; Architectural models; Tufts University
    - Archictural model of Wessell Library, plan view, 1963; UA021.001.010.00016.00007; Unknown (Box 10)
      Libraries; Plan views; Architectural models; Tufts University
  - Wessell Library, 1960 -- 1983; UA021.001.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - Wessell Library: Man and Pegasus, 1966 -- 1968; UA021.001.011.00002 (Box 11)
  - Wessell Library: Milles' Elephant, 1964 -- 1965; UA021.001.011.00003 (Box 11)
    - Milles Fountain in the courtyard of Wessell Library, 1965; UA021.001.011.00003.00001; Unknown (Box 11)
      Libraries; Fountains; Elephants; Tufts University
  - Wilson House, 1937; UA021.001.011.00004 (Box 11)
  - Wren Hall, 1965 -- 1966; UA021.001.011.00005 (Box 11)
  - West Hall, 1889 -- 1969; UA021.001.011.00006 (Box 11)
    - Entrance to West Hall, 1955; UA021.001.011.00006.00001; Unknown (Box 11)
      Buildings; Entrances; Tufts University
    - View northwest from Bubble including West Hall, 1910 -- 1935; UA021.001.011.00006.00002; Munro, Melville S. (Box 11)
      2
    - West Hall viewed through trees, 1950; UA021.001.011.00006.00003; Unknown (Box 11)
      Buildings; Trees; Tufts University
    - West Hall, 1900; UA021.001.011.00006.00004; Unknown (Box 11)
    - Front elevation of West Hall, 1889; UA021.001.011.00006.00005; Unknown (Box 11)
      Buildings; Elevations (drawings); Tufts University
    - View of West Hall looking north from Ballou Hall, 1889; UA021.001.011.00006.00006; Unknown (Box 11)
      Buildings; Dormitories; Exterior views; Trees; Tufts University
    - Frontal view of West Hall, 1889; UA021.001.011.00006.00007; Unknown (Box 11)
  - General correspondence, 1878 -- 1936; UA021.001.011.00007 (Box 11)
  - General, 1938 -- 1970; UA021.001.012.00001 (Box 12)
  - General, miscellaneous, 1950 -- 1965; UA021.001.012.00002 (Box 12)
  - Photos, 1850 -- 1910; UA021.001.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - Photos, 1920; UA021.001.012.00004 (Box 12)
  - Photos, 1890; UA021.001.012.00005 (Box 12)
  - Photos, 1890; UA021.001.012.00006 (Box 12)
  - Photos of gates, steps, and fences, 1890 -- 1950; UA021.001.013.00001 (Box 13)
  - Gates, steps, and fences, 1920 -- 1983; UA021.001.013.00002 (Box 13)
  - Photos, 1900 -- 1983; UA021.001.013.00003 (Box 13)
  - Photos, snow scenes, 1930 -- 1940; UA021.001.013.00004 (Box 13)
  - Aeriel views of campus, 1950; UA021.001.013.00005 (Box 13)
  - Energy conservation, 1936 -- 1973; UA021.001.013.00006 (Box 13)
  - Cannon, 1975; UA021.001.013.00007 (Box 13)
  - Gravity Research Foundation, 1961 -- 1962; UA021.001.013.00008 (Box 13)
  - Land, 1869 -- 1952; UA021.001.013.00009 (Box 13)
  - Mystic River Watershed Association, 1970 -- 1974; UA021.001.014.00001 (Box 14)
  - Oval, 1950 -- 1973; UA021.001.014.00002 (Box 14)
  - Maps and diagrams, 1900 -- 1976; UA021.001.014.00003 (Box 14)
    - Map of Tufts College, 1929; UA021.001.014.00003.00001 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 3)
      Medford Campus; Tufts University
  - Physical Plant Department, 1979 -- 1988; UA021.001.014.00004 (Box 14)
  - Medford, 1883 -- 1980; UA021.001.014.00005 (Box 14)
  - Medford, 1897 -- 1979; UA021.001.014.00006 (Box 14)
    - View of Tufts College featuring the President's House, Professors Row, Metcalf Hall, the Chapel, Eaton Memorial Library, Miner Hall, and Paige Hall, 1897; UA021.001.014.00006.00001; Unknown (Box 14)
      Buildings; Roads; Universities and colleges; Tufts University
    - Medford residents abutting new dorm site stage a protest, 1978-03-25; UA021.001.014.00006.00002; Jet Commercial Photographers (Box 14)
      People; Activism; Signs; Tufts University
    - Protest over new dorms, 1978; UA021.001.014.00006.00003; Jet Commercial Photographers (Box 14)
    - Medford residents abutting new dorm site on College Avenue stage a protest, 1978-03-25; UA021.001.014.00006.00004; Unknown (Box 14)
      People; Signs; Activism; Tufts University
    - Dog with sign protesting new dorms, 1978; UA021.001.014.00006.00005; Jet Commercial Photographers (Box 14)
      Dogs; Activism; Signs; Tufts University
  - Reservoir, 1875 -- 1967; UA021.001.015.00001 (Box 15)
  - Somerville, 1878 -- 1980; UA021.001.015.00002 (Box 15)
  - Stearns Village, 1946 -- 1988; UA021.001.015.00003 (Box 15)
  - Trees, 1927 -- 1939; UA021.001.015.00004 (Box 15)
  - Walnut Hill Properties, 1977; UA021.001.015.00005 (Box 15)
  - Service Employee Union, 1943 -- 1994; UA021.001.016.00001 (Box 16)
  - Safe, Sure, Secure, (Accident Prevention Guide), 1976; UA021.001.016.00002 (Box 16)
  - Specifications for Men's and Women's Dormitories, 1958; UA021.001.016.00003 (Box 16)
  - Art objects, 1953; UA021.001.017.00001 (Box 17)
  - Art objects, Inventories, 1854 -- 1982; UA021.001.017.00002 (Box 17)
    A copy of the complete 1970 art inventory currently at the Art Gallery (furniture, art etc) is photocopied in a binder behind the front desk; careful, the 1970 inventory is only a partial inventory of objects on campus at the time.